A Guide to the Warren County (Va.) Records, 1818-1990 circa
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Warren County (Va.) Records, 1818-1990 circa
The Library of Virginia
1013582-1176240 circa
12 boxes and or volumes.
Warren County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a shipment of court papers from Warren County. Portions of the collection were transferred under the following accession numbers: 33162e, 37474, 37575, 37576, 37577, 37582, 37583, 37584, 37585, 37586, 37587, 37588, 37589, 37590, 37591, 37593, 37594, 37595, and 37596.
Historical Information
Warren County was named for Joseph Warren, the revolutionary patriot who sent Paul Revere and William Dawes on their famous rides and who was killed at the Battle of Bunker Hill. The county was formed from Frederick and Shenandoah counties in 1836.
Scope and Content
Warren County (Va.) Records, 1818-1990 circa includes miscellaneous records from the folling series: Court Records, Land Records, Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, Fiduciary Records, Military and Pension Records, Tax and Fiscal Records, Road and Bridge Records, County Administrative Records, Wills, Marriage and Vital Statistics Records, School Records, Miscellaneous Records, and Election Records.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Warren County Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm"
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Warren County (Va.) Circuit Court
Subjects:
Public Records--Virginia--Warren County
Geographical Names:
Warren County (Va.)--History
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Warren County
Contents List
- Records, 1852-1910
  Box 197 contains Railroad Condemnations: Shenandoah Valley Railroad Company Records which includes commissioner reports and plats and damages allowed to landholders in Warren County from Manakin Railroad Company. Land Records: Plats of Gardner lands. Bonds/Commissions/Oaths: Loyalty Oaths, 1861, Oaths of Office, 1866-1910.
- Records, 1840-1908
  Box 247 contains Court Records from the Circuit Court of Law and Chancery. Injunction Bonds, Liquor License Bonds, Recognizances. Deeds, Fiduciary Records, and Orders and Memos(1841).
- Records, 1836-1893
  Box 246 contains Ministers Bonds, Officials Bonds, Executors, Administrators, and Guardian Bonds. Fiduciary Accounts and Bonds.
- Records, 1836-1947
  Box 250 contains Road Papers, Orders and Contracts(1836-1918 circa); Estrays(1836-1885), and Coroners Inquests (1869, 1872, 1938-1947).
- Records, 1889-1904 and 1888-1891
  This volume contains Taxes on Deeds, 1889-1904 and Confederate Pensioners Records, 1888-1891.
- Records, 1818-1919 circa
  Box 1 contains Bonds, Commissions, Oaths: Officials' Commissions, 1836-1862, Accession Number 37474. Military and Pension Records: Local Board List of Registrants for World War I (Alphabetical); Local Board World War I Minute Book, (2 volumes); Local Board World War I Records (includes correspondence, Minutes, List of Soldiers, and List of Registrants, Accession Number 37586. Military and Pension Records: Muster Rolls, 149th Regiment Virginia Militia. Accession Number 37584. Military and Pension Records: Pension Records, 1818-1857 (includes applications, documentation, and forms). Accession Number 37585. Military and Pension Records: Military Orders, 1868-1870. Accession Number 37591. Miscellaneous Records: Public Buildings and Grounds: Plans, Specifications, Bonds, Reports for Courthouse, Clerk's Office, and Jail. Accession Number 37589 (1 of 2). Various Series: Court Records, Election Records, Road & Bridge Records, and Miscellaneous Records. Accession Number 37589 (2 of 2). Miscellaneous Records: Sundry Forms not in Form Book (includes suit papers) Accession Number 37588.
- ,Records, 1840-1936 circa
  Box 2 contains Bonds, Commissions, Oaths: Justice of the Peace Commissions, 1870, Accession Number 37575. Court Records: Judgments, September-October 1840, Accession Number 37576. Orphan chancery causes; Election Records: Democratic Canvass Book, 1885, Accession Number 37577. Election Certificates, 1864-1866; List of Voters, 1857-1865; Commissioners of Elections, 1857-1865; Pollbook, 1865, Accession Number 37582. Road and Bridge Records: Allottment of Hands, 1936, Accession Number 37593. Toll Gate Records, 1917-1918' Accession Number 37594. Toll Fund Accounts, Chester's Gap Gate, Front Royal District, 1917-1918, Accession Number 37594. Toll Fund Accounts, Manor Gate, Front Royal District, 1917-1918, Accession Number 37594. Toll Fund Accounts, Lewin Gate, Front Royal District, 1917-1918, Accession Number 37594. School Records: Front Royal Academy papers, 1847 (includes building plans, bills) Accession Number 37595. Treasurer Records: Settlements with Board of Supervisors, 1888-1898, Accession Number 37596. Miscellaneous Records: Distribution of Food to indigent Families, 1862-1864, Accession Number 37583. Charter of First Fire Company, 1887., Accession Number 37590. Lord Fairfax Papers (includes Deeds, Wills, Election, and Sheriff Receipts) Accession Number 37587. Township records, 1870, Accession Number 37587. Letter - C. T. Westen to Colonel E. B. Jacobs, June 14,1862, Accession Number 33162e.
- Records, 1861-1882 circa
  Box 20 contains Land Records: Assignments of Bankruptcy; Assorted Deeds recorded in Deed Book K, 1875-1877, Deed Numbers 296, 211,320. Deed recorded in Deed Book J, 1871-1875, Deed Number 176; List of property found in Deed Book H, 1861-1871. Renunciation of Will, 1882 and a Marriage Contract.
- Records 1840-1936 circa
  This collection includes Court Records: Judgments and petitions, and Fiduciary Records.
- Records, 1836-1865
  These volumes contains School Records: School Commissioners' Record Book, 1836-1864 and School Fund Accounts, 1862-1864. Court Records: Circuit Court Minutes for March 1863 through August 1864. Military and Pension Records: Records of the County Board of Exemption, 1862. Tax and Fiscal Records: Salt Distribution Register, 1863-1865.
- Records, 1822-1990 circa
  Box 3 contains Bonds, Commissions, Oaths, 1839-1990 circa; Clerk's Records, 1822-1900; Court Finance, 1841-1858; Election Records, 1840-1860; and Road and Bridge Records, 1841-1889.
- Records, 1801-1911 circa
  Box 4 contains Fiduciary Records, 1830-1911 circa; Jury Records, 1857; Land Records, 1883-1905; Military and Pension Records, circa 1801-1861; Miscellaneous Records, 1836-1901; Naturalization Records, 1852-1855, and Overseers of the Poor Records, 1851-1856.